<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Just Another Geek</title>
    <link>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Just Another Geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 20:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a bit of Web paranoia into my habits...</title>
      <link>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2011/09/Introducing-a-bit-of-Web-paranoia-into-my-habits.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2011/09/Introducing-a-bit-of-Web-paranoia-into-my-habits.../</guid>
      <description>When I&amp;rsquo;m not slacking in Emacs, I now spend most of my time in Google Chrome. Almost everything I do is in the &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; (I hate this buzz word): mail, blog, chats, voip and even version control.
With the explosion of &amp;ldquo;social buttons&amp;rdquo; everywhere, I became really more paranoid than before about my privacy. And when I see new Facebook &amp;lsquo;Frictionless sharing&amp;rsquo; feature, I don&amp;rsquo;t regret my move. What did I do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>net2pcap revival</title>
      <link>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2011/08/net2pcap-revival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 14:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2011/08/net2pcap-revival/</guid>
      <description>net2pcap is a packet capture tool written by Philippe Biondi back in 2003. It was designed to be as secure as possible in order to be run in hostile environment. To do so, its code is minimalist without any complicate feature, the result is 406 lines of simple C. On top of its security, it is also the most reliable tool I have ever used on high traffic link regarding packet loss, even dumpcap does not perform better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Security, one year later...</title>
      <link>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2011/01/Linux-Security-one-year-later.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 22:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2011/01/Linux-Security-one-year-later.../</guid>
      <description>This post (tries to) describe what happened in 2010 about GNU/Linux security. What this post is not is a long list of vulnerabilities, there are some people doing it way better that me.
The first part of this post is dedicated to new vulnerability classes where the second one focuses on the defensive side, analyzing improvements made to the Linux kernel. Before closing this post, some selected quotes will be presented, pointing the finger at some of the Linux failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La sécurité sous Linux, un an plus tard...</title>
      <link>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2010/12/La-s%C3%A9curit%C3%A9-sous-Linux-un-an-plus-tard.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 15:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2010/12/La-s%C3%A9curit%C3%A9-sous-Linux-un-an-plus-tard.../</guid>
      <description>Sorry english folks: this post is in french, but it will be translated soon, translated and updated post is available here.
Plus qu&amp;rsquo;une longue liste de vulnérabilités, ce post a pour objectif de décrire ce qu&amp;rsquo;il s&amp;rsquo;est passé en 2010 dans l&amp;rsquo;écosystème de la sécurité sous GNU/Linux.
La première partie est dédiée aux nouvelles classes de vulnérabilité. La deuxième partie se concentre sur la défense avec l&amp;rsquo;analyse des différentes améliorations tendant à améliorer la sécurité de nos systèmes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document review of Qubes OS</title>
      <link>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2010/04/Document-review-of-Qubes-OS/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://justanothergeek.chdir.org/2010/04/Document-review-of-Qubes-OS/</guid>
      <description>Qubes OS You must have heard about it, Invisible Things Lab released their own operating system, named Qubes OS (If you ask me, I would have refer to it as a Linux distribution instead). Their distribution focuses on security isolation and is based on their virtualization experience (for the record, Joanna and Rafal are the people behind most of the virtualization vulnerabilities found in the previous years).
 Disclaimer: I do not had the occasion to test the system, this post is only based on my reading of their (great) QubesOs architecture paper (version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>